# **JASON WEST**

# Madison Heights, MI 48071 248.854.2130 jasonlwest@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jasonlwest/ | GitHub: https://github.com/jlw429

Portfolio: <a href="https://jlw429.github.io/PortfolioHW2/">https://jlw429.github.io/PortfolioHW2/</a>

#### SUMMARY:

Full Stack professional coming from a background in retail management with extensive experience in team building and Human Resources. Full stack certificate from Michigan State University, with experience in JavaScript, React, Mongo.db, CSS, HTML, Node.js, and currently learning Python. Bachelor of Science degree from the University of Central Florida. Understanding of Scrum and Agile methodology, highly skilled at building a cohesive team, delegation, as well as praising and holding people accountable. Have always had a passion to learn computer science fundamentals so I made the decision to move on from retail and become skilled in the full-stack technologies. Consider myself a quick learner, focused and pays attention to the little things as well as having problem solving abilities and determination.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, MySQL, Jquery, Bootstrap, Node.js, Express, Handlebars, ReactJS.

Applications: Git, Terminal, JIRA, Bash, Git project manager.

### PROJECTS:

Thats My Jam | GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/jlw429/MusicArtists">https://github.io/MusicArtists/#</a>
A way for the user to learn more about an artist they may have heard on TikTok or the radio. It gives a short biography of the artist or band, you also have their top 50 songs and the app has the technology to show the music video from youTube that populates as a modul in the middle of the page. The app was built from scratch using Javascript, Jquery, Bootstrap, CSS, HTML and using APIs from the audio database, last.fm, and youtube.

**Weather Dashboard** | GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/jlw429/HW6Weather">https://jlw429.github.io/HW6Weather</a>/ App was developed for a quick way to type in a city, get the city, current conditions and five day forecast. Utilizing API's from openweathermap as well as Jquery, Javascript, Bootstrap, CSS, and HTML. The app was created from scratch.

**Team Builder** | GitHub Repository: <a href="https://github.com/jlw429/TeamManagerHW10">https://github.com/jlw429/TeamManagerHW10</a>

This app was created to help a new leader become accustomed to his/her team. You build the app yourself and will ask if you are building a profile for a manager, engineer or intern. The app was built from scratch and used TDD testing with the jest npm technology. Languages used: Node.js inquirer npm module, jest npm module, Jquery, Bootstrap, CSS, HTML.

**Day Planner** | GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/jlw429/DatePlannerHW5">https://github.com/jlw429/DatePlannerHW5</a> | Website: <a href="https://jlw429.github.io/DatePlannerHW5/">https://jlw429.github.io/DatePlannerHW5/</a> The busy professionals' best friend! The app runs from 7 to 7 for any professional to set up their work day. The current hour has a red hue over it, future times have green and past times are red. It saves to local storage. All work was created solely by myself. Technologies used were Jquery, moment.js, javascript, css, bootstrap, HTML.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

# The Kroger Company | Store Manager (2017 – 2020) / Operations Assistant Store Manager (2016 – 2017)

Increase customer satisfaction while bringing strategic direction to my team to help achieve departmental goals. Maintain a positive attitude and presence on the sales floor. Adjust weekly sales forecasts while accounting for sales trends and seasons. Educate associates on new processes and procedures promoting continuity in the workplace. Ensure ample team members are on hand when finalizing work schedules. Hire new team members and process paperwork while adhering to FMLA, labor, and OSHA requirements. Write and submit job descriptions for various positions in the store.

- Boosted employee morale while achieving best practice initiatives aimed at improving efficiency.
- Recognized among peers for being the voice of reason and someone to turn to for sound advice.
- Mentored and trained Assistant Managers and Department Managers to retain and help them grow in the company.
- Minimized shrink by 5% while coaching and developing associates and managers on best practices.
- Transformed an overnight grocery stocking crew from wasting overtime and productivity to having a well-stocked high- performance environment in just six months.
- Lead staff meetings daily where briefly every supervisor reports out sales, wages, and any news that is happening in the department

## Publix Supermarkets, Inc. | Assistant Store Manager (2012 – 2016) / Customer Service Manager (2008-2012)

Hired and dismissed team members as needed. Ensured legal compliance while handling sensitive and confidential information and documents. Resolved conflicts between employees promoting a cohesive team while boosting morale and providing top-notch customer service. Designed, tracked, and analyzed store reports. Managed projects while producing positive results. Met corporate goals and forecasted weekly sales.

- Led and directed a team of 150+ individuals within a supermarket averaging \$450-600K in sales weekly.
- Worked on a special project with three other assistant store managers to re-developing district policies regarding shoplifting. This process lowered unidentified shrink 7% throughout the district. This was then sent to enterprise for consideration to make it a company-wide policy.
- Propelled the division to improve Workers Compensation claims helping the store win the 2013 Safety Award for the Atlanta division.

#### **EDUCATION:**

## Full Stack Certificate | Michigan State University, East Lansing, MI

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

## Bachelor of Science | University of Central Florida, Orlando, FL

Major in Health Care Administration, Minor in Health Information Management.